<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Async]]></title><description><![CDATA[An inclusive web tech meetup based in Brighton, UK]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:48:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asyncjs.com/feed/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Async Christmas Quiz 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back for another Async Christmas Quiz! Despite all the challenges, it’s been a great year in Async-land, with great talks on everything from Accessibility to React Native, as well as some cracking community events such as Ask the Brains and the Show’n’Tell.</p>
<p>Come join us to round it off in style with Quizmaster Daniel van Berzon. As with last year, this will not be a test of how much JavaScript you know as we want to welcome people at all stages of their career; instead it’ll be more of a pub-style quiz but with the focus on having a great time together. So get your metaphorical (or real) Santa hat and beard on and sign up!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz-2021</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://secure.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/9/d/b/0/clean_500080368.jpeg</url><title>Christmas Pug</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/dapuglet/49233631602/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Daniel van Berzon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Two-Dimensional Show'n'Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The nights are coming earlier and the wind is blowing cooler, but Async is here to take your mind off the end of &quot;summer&quot; with another of our world famous Show&#39;n&#39;Tells!</p>
<p>The meeting will be taking place on zoom, so please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/281637443/">meetup.com</a> to get access to the link.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re interested in giving a talk, we&#39;d love to hear from you. It&#39;s the perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind. You’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web.</p>
<p>If you would like to grab a speaking slot, please leave a comment on the <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/281637443/">meetup event</a> including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your name</li>
<li>Your main website, if you have one</li>
<li>Twitter username, if you have one</li>
<li>A sentence or two about your talk</li>
<li>Any relevant links</li>
</ul>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/two-dimensional-show-n-tell/">2020</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2019/">2019</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018/">2018</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/two-dimensional-show-n-tell-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/two-dimensional-show-n-tell-2021</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://secure.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/a/a/4/5/clean_499723589.jpeg</url><title>Two Dimensional Show n&apos; Tell</title><link>https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/281637443</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to prevent the collapse of society by building an accessible web]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It’s 2031. Society, as we knew it in 2021, has officially collapsed. Broken hardware and a very slow internet connection are all we have left.</p>
<p>Accessibility on the web is now paramount to the survival of the human race. </p>
<p>But how do you ensure your website is accessible amidst a raging apocalypse?</p>
<p>Join <a href="https://whitep4nth3r.com/">whitep4nth3r</a> to explore why only the most accessible and inclusive websites will survive an apocalypse, how you can utilise free tools to ensure you are building for the apocalypse, and why all of this is more important than ever now, in 2021.</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/save-the-world-with-a11y</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/save-the-world-with-a11y</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://www.publicdomainpictures.net/pictures/200000/velka/nuclear-bomb-explosion.jpg</url><title>Nuclear Bomb Explosion</title><link>https://www.publicdomainpictures.net/en/view-image.php?image=198310&amp;picture=nuclear-bomb-explosion</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Salma Alam-Naylor ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating offline and 'instant' websites - aka Progressive Web Apps]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The term Progressive Web Apps can be misleading, implying some framework/library or special architecture. In reality, PWAs are regular websites that use HTML5 APIs to create offline sites that have near instant speed. Anything less than 100ms is deemed &#39;instant&#39; by the brain.</p>
<p>Using HTML5&#39;s Cache API, we can effectively create a local web server on the user&#39;s device hosting web pages. With IndexedDB, we have a powerful asynchronous database in the browser. In this way, we can have a &#39;local&#39; deployment of our site.</p>
<p>The magic comes alive with Service Workers... JavaScript files that can intercept network requests and serve pages either from the cache or the network. Service Workers also connect the website with the OS, enabling us to implement many of the features of mobile apps. Google&#39;s Project Fugu has as its mission to enable a PWA to be able to do everything that a mobile app can.</p>
<p>In this talk, we will work with a repo site both locally and live on the Internet so that we can see how this is achieved... breaking and repairing the site as we developers learn best. It is a generic boilerplate for PWAs and can therefore form the basis for you to add offline/instant capability to your existing sites.</p>
<p>All resources and additional links to course videos will be available to attendees.</p>
<h3 id="bio">BIO:</h3>
<p>Craig is a trainer/developer of PWAs, Web Components, RxJS and GraphQL with a strong emphasis on databases. He currently provides training courses for NDC and is a regular volunteer tutor at CodeYourFuture.io. <a href="https://github.com/iwswordpress/">https://github.com/iwswordpress/</a></p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/pwas</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/pwas</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d5/Progressive_Web_Apps_Logo.svg</url><title>PWA logo</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Progressive_Web_Apps_Logo.svg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Craig West ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Startup Patterns and Practices]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As web developers, chances are that at some point in our careers we might work for a startup, or even found one ourselves. These opportunities are exhilarating and intense, but are there ways we can increase the chances of being part of the small percentage of startups that make it big? That&#39;s the focus of August&#39;s Async.</p>
<p>From the speaker:</p>
<p>&quot;I was a ex CTO of a startup and now a solution architect at AWS in the startup team. I am working with startup companies that have 1 to 500 developers. These companies range from household names to small companies working on a passion. This session will dive into the good &amp; bad and the does &amp; don&#39;ts of startup.</p>
<p>I will talk about the hot technologies, the not so hot ideas and patterns that get applied and misapplied. What goes around and comes around in the world of software development.</p>
<p>Along the way we will discover what works and what does not.&quot;</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/startup-patterns</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/startup-patterns</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/startup_patterns.jpg</url><title>Image of laptop with ideas sprouting forth</title><link>https://www.pxfuel.com/en/search?q=evaluation</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Andrew Cheeseman ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Design systems in React Native]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>David Leuliette will be taking us from zero to hero with React Native thanks to the power of design systems. No prior knowledge of React or React Native will be required.</p>
<p>From David:</p>
<p>&quot;With React Native, you style your application using JavaScript. The more you add developers and features, the more design consistency problems and pain points will appear.</p>
<p>Let&#39;s explore together how to create a first-class developer experience when managing styles and themes with restyle and storybook!&quot;</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/react-native-design-systems</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/react-native-design-systems</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a7/React-icon.svg?download</url><title>React icon</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/React_(JavaScript_library)</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ David Leuliette ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Night with Vue]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;ll have two talks for June&#39;s Async, giving us a comprehensive overview of Vue.js. First up, we&#39;ll have Phil Lennon with &quot;A Brief Introduction to Vue.js&quot;.</p>
<p>From Phil: &quot;I will cover the differences between React and Vue, the Vue ecosystem (for example interesting packages such as Vuetify Material Design), Vue 3 and it&#39;s impact, the choice between Vue 2 and Vue 3, and some very basic examples of use.&quot;</p>
<p>With that information under our belts, we&#39;ll see what Nuxt.js can bring to the table courtesy of Daniel Roe and his talk &quot;Diving into Nuxt: Zero to Hero&quot;.</p>
<p>From Daniel: &quot;We&#39;ll build a Nuxt project together from scratch. Nuxt is a progressive Vue framework meant to make web development simpler - so it&#39;ll be a whistle-stop tour of the ways you can make your life easier. We&#39;ll look at server-side rendering, bundle splitting, image optimisation, automatic route generation and more. Along the way, fire your questions at me and I&#39;ll do my best to answer them.</p>
<p>The talk will assume no previous Nuxt or Vue experience but I&#39;ll also be sharing tips and tricks I&#39;ve garnered through SaaS and enterprise software development.&quot;</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/a-night-with-vue</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/a-night-with-vue</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/95/Vue.js_Logo_2.svg/1200px-Vue.js_Logo_2.svg.png</url><title>Vue.js logo</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vue.js</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Phil Lennon, Daniel Roe ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Online Brains, Autumn 2020]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;ve had two Ask the Online Brains sessions since the start of this pandemic, and it&#39;s time for what will hopefully be our last one where we&#39;re all joining from our kitchen tables/bedrooms/shepherd&#39;s huts.</p>
<p>If you haven&#39;t joined one before, don&#39;t worry they&#39;re super easy to get involved in at any level that&#39;s most comfortable for you.</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly Brighton ALT.NET meetup (<a href="http://brightonalt.net/">http://brightonalt.net/</a>), we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web-related - 5 - 10 minutes per topic.</p>
<p>The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their &quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot; type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does &quot;this&quot; mean in JavaScript?</li>
<li>null or undefined, or is there a case for both</li>
<li>Do we have to accept that JavaScript is now a compiled language</li>
<li>How do you maintain a work-life balance</li>
<li>Should I write unit tests, integration tests, or both?</li>
<li>What are the beneficial aspects of Agile/Scrum, and what do you find less useful.</li>
</ul>
<p>You will be able to submit topics, and event attendees will be able to vote for the topics they would like to discuss. We will run the online discussion for about an hour, and afterwards, anyone who wishes to stay can share a virtual pint.</p>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>So, please put your thinking caps on now and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask.</p>
<hr>
<p>The Zoom will be open from 7.30pm so please feel free to join early and have a general catch up :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains-3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains-3</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/20/Roundtable_meeting_of_leaders_at_Belt_and_Road_international_forum.jpg</url><title>Roundtable meeting of leaders at Belt and Road international forum</title><link>https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Roundtable_meeting_of_leaders_at_Belt_and_Road_international_forum.jpg</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Testing made simple]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Testing your changes before they make it to production is crucial to ensure high-quality and robust software. When Stefan started web development in 2006, testing was not widely adopted and rather an exception.</p>
<p>Due to the increasing complexity of web applications over the past 10 years, testing has become a necessary part of most developers&#39; lives. There are plenty of different strategies and even more tools and libraries available to get you going. Balancing the different strategies is a real challenge, and has a huge impact on the developer experience as well as the quality of your product.</p>
<p>In this talk, Stefan will give us first-hand insights into how he approaches testing for <a href="https://octolinker.now.sh/">OctoLinker</a> to make the contributor experience as easy as possible. He will also cover how he is using the GitHub API to test <a href="https://pullrequestbadge.com/">Pull Request Badge</a> End 2 End.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/buckstefan">Stefan Buck</a> is a Software Engineer at Brandwatch. Prior to that, he was working for companies in different industries such as agencies, automotive, and as a full-time OSS framework maintainer. He has a strong product and developer focused mindset, as well as a keen desire to create great developer experiences</p>
<hr>
<p>The Zoom will be open from 7.30pm so please feel free to join early and have a general catch up :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/e2e-testing</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/e2e-testing</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://octolinker.now.sh/static/octolinker.png</url><title>Octolinker logo</title><link>https://octolinker.now.sh/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Stefan Buck ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fullstack Jamstack Development with RedwoodJS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>RedwoodJS is a fullstack serverless framework for the Jamstack that combines a variety of modern technologies including React, GraphQL, and Prisma. In this talk, Anthony Campolo (RedwoodJS Core Advocate), will explain the origins and motivations behind RedwoodJS. He will also demonstrate how to create a RedwoodJS app from scratch and deploy it to the internet.</p>
<hr>
<p>The Zoom will be open from 7.30pm so please feel free to join early and have a general catch up :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/redwoodjs</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/redwoodjs</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/02931d36f812dbcc6a3e41f05d133a7cdcace063/949ca/images/stickers.png</url><title>stickers</title><link>https://redwoodjs.com</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Anthony Campolo ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[ARIA Ready to Learn About Accessibility?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Abby Mitchell will be giving us the low down on a crucial aspect of every web developer&#39;s life - accessibility. </p>
<p>Web Accessibility is an important aspect of software development to know about for anyone building anything for the web. Or for anyone working with anyone building anything for the web. Or for anyone who even knows anyone building anything for the web. Basically, if you care about making the world (which nowadays is increasingly synonymous with the digital world) a more inclusive place for people with disabilities and impairments, then learning about web accessibility is a must. 
This talk aims to give a broad overview of web accessibility for those keen to get their feet wet in this interesting, yet often overlooked, area of web development. The talk will cover the basic What, Why and How of the topic, giving you a starting point from which to develop your interest/skills going forward.</p>
<p>Abby is a Full Stack Web Developer working at IBM in London. She is a primarily self-taught developer, with a passion for code, puns and making the digital world a more inclusive place.</p>
<hr>
<p>The Zoom will be open from 7.30pm so please feel free to join early and have a general catch up :)</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/web-accessibility</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/web-accessibility</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://miro.medium.com/max/8000/1*0wPF7It_4j7vmqmKzyrMtg.jpeg</url><title>web accessibility icon</title><link>https://uxplanet.org/web-accessibility-explained-c2408636eee0</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Abby Mitchell ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Async Christmas Quiz]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the first ever Async Christmas Quiz! As we welcome web tech loving folk of all levels of experience, this will <em>not</em> be a quiz about how much JavaScript you know - it&#39;s a community quiz more in line with a traditional pub quiz. So please come along, either as a team or by yourself, and let&#39;s send off this rotten year in style!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://unsplash.com/photos/49uySSA678U/download?force=true&amp;w=640</url><title>https://unsplash.com/photos/49uySSA678U</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Pete Goodman, Daniel van Berzon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Unifying frameworks with Web Components]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Web Components, or Custom HTML tags, allow us to create our own custom HTML tags that are native to the browser. They can be used as a modular library for organisations, or be used to create complete applications using &#39;the platform&#39;.</p>
<p>They are used like regular HTML tags so can be built in to JS Frameworks. Furthermore, many JS Frameworks enable their components to be exported as Web Components. This gives us the possibility to create apps that contain many different frameworks that do not just exist with each other, but can interact with each other.</p>
<p>In this talk, we will look at what Web Components are and how they can be made. We will look at the architecture of a multi-framework app.</p>
<p>A video of using Web Components to convert a monolithic app into a set of micro-apps/services is available at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FpTPcIlWjA4">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FpTPcIlWjA4</a></p>
<p>The Github repo is available at <a href="https://github.com/iwswordpress/">https://github.com/iwswordpress/</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/unifying-frameworks-with-web-components</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/unifying-frameworks-with-web-components</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/web-component-logo.png</url><title>Web Component logo</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Craig West ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Online Brains, Autumn 2020]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>2020 rumbles on and no sign of us being able to all meet up in person anytime in the near future sadly. To cheer ourselves up, we&#39;re having a re-run of the popular and successful Ask the Brains session we had back in May. For those new to the format, here&#39;s a recap:</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly Brighton ALT.NET meetup (<a href="http://brightonalt.net/">http://brightonalt.net/</a>), we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web-related - 5 - 10 minutes per topic.</p>
<p>The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their &quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot; type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does <code>this</code> mean in JavaScript?</li>
<li><code>null</code> or <code>undefined</code>, or is there a case for both</li>
<li>Do we have to accept that JavaScript is now a compiled language</li>
<li>How do you maintain a work-life balance</li>
<li>Should I write unit tests, integration tests, or both?</li>
<li>What are the beneficial aspects of Agile/Scrum, and what do you find less useful.</li>
</ul>
<p>You will be able to submit topics, and event attendees will be able to vote for the topics they would like to discuss. We will run the online discussion for about an hour, and afterwards, anyone who wishes to stay can share a virtual pint.</p>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>So, please put your thinking caps on now and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask.</p>
<p>We highly recommend you sign up to the Async Slack channel for more info, and updates.</p>
<p><a href="https://asyncjs.com/about/">https://asyncjs.com/about/</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains-2</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 19:45:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/2503/3792906411_d3f8762924_w_d.jpg</url><title>Brains</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/neilconway/3792906411</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Teaching code as a foreign language]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>How can you set developers up for success? Think like an English teacher.</p>
<p>The days of grammar drills and awkward roleplays may be behind us, but there’s more than a passing similarity between learning a foreign language and learning to code. Just like English, French and Klingon, programming languages like JavaScript and Go are underpinned by systems (grammar and vocabulary) and skills (reading and writing), so why shouldn’t we use the same approach to teach them?</p>
<p>Drawing on my own experience teaching English as a foreign language, I’ll take you through some of the most useful language-teaching techniques and how you can use them in a technical context - whether you&#39;re coaching a new developer on your team, or writing documentation for a bank employing hundreds of developers.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/teaching-code-as-a-foreign-language</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/teaching-code-as-a-foreign-language</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/7150/6697055189_f947d7a7a7_z_d.jpg</url><title>teacher meme</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/ptica10/6697055189/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Sophie Koonin ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Two Dimensional Show n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Following the success of <a href="https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains/">Ask the Online Brains</a>, and with regular programming still suspended, we have decided to run an online version of another classic Async event. On Thurs 2nd July 2020 at 19:30 we are organising a <strong>&quot;Two dimensional Show and Tell&quot;</strong>.</p>
<p>This will be an online version of the <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2019/">International show and tell</a> that we run every year before <a href="https://ffconf.org/">FFConf</a>. It&#39;ll be a great opportunity to watch a variety of speakers each give a five-minute presentation on something exciting related to the web.</p>
<p>The meeting will be taking place on zoom, so please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/271442327/">meetup.com</a> to get access to the link.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re interested in giving a talk, we&#39;d love to hear from you. It&#39;s the perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind. You’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web.</p>
<p>If you would like to grab a speaking slot, please leave a comment on the <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/271442327/">meetup event</a> including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your name</li>
<li>Your main website, if you have one</li>
<li>Twitter username, if you have one</li>
<li>A sentence or two about your talk</li>
<li>Any relevant links</li>
</ul>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2019/">2019</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018/">2018</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/two-dimensional-show-n-tell</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/two-dimensional-show-n-tell</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 07:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/two-d-show-n-tell.jpg</url><title>Two Dimensional Show n&apos; Tell</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Online Brains, Spring 2020]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>What with one thing and another, and with regular programming suspended, we&#39;ve decided to have a go at a virtual Async event.</p>
<p>On the evening of 21 May, we will be hosting on an online version of our popular <strong>&quot;Ask the Brains&quot;</strong> event. Inspired by the monthly Brighton <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">ALT.NET meetup</a>, we will be asking/talking/ranting about everything web-related - 5 - 10 minutes per topic.</p>
<p>The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their <em>&quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot;</em> type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does <code>this</code> mean in Javascript?</li>
<li><code>null</code> or <code>undefined</code>, or is there a case for both</li>
<li>Do we have to accept that JavaScript is now a compiled language</li>
<li>How do you maintain a work-life balance</li>
<li>Should I write unit tests, integration tests, or both?</li>
<li>What are the beneficial aspects of Agile/Scrum, and what do you find less useful.</li>
</ul>
<p>You will be able to submit topics, and event attendees will be able to vote for the topics they would like to discuss. We will run the online discussion for about an hour, and afterwards, anyone who wishes to stay can share a virtual pint.</p>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>So, please put your thinking caps on now and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask.</p>
<p>Please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/270599931/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the Async Slack channel for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-online-brains</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/brains.jpg</url><title>Ask the online brains</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[How we built the web in five days]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The World Wide Web turned 30 years old this year. To mark the occasion, a motley group of web nerds gathered at CERN, the birthplace of the web, to build a time machine. The first ever web browser was, confusingly, called WorldWideWeb. What if we could recreate the experience of using it ...but within a modern browser! Join (Je)Remy on a journey through time and space and code as they excavate the foundations of Tim Berners-Lee&#39;s gloriously ambitious and hacky hypertext system that went on to conquer the world.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/how-we-built-the-web-in-five-days</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/how-we-built-the-web-in-five-days</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://worldwideweb.cern.ch/images/colophon/thegroup.jpg</url><title>Jeremy and Remy at Cern</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Jeremy Keith, Remy Sharp ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Future of AR/VR on the Web]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Ada Rose Cannon will present the future of augmented and virtual reality on the web. More details to be confirmed.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/future-of-ar-vr-on-the-web</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/future-of-ar-vr-on-the-web</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://i.imgur.com/UFYgx1Y.png</url><title>VR Is The Future.</title><link>https://imgur.com/gallery/UFYgx1Y</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Ada Rose Cannon ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Learning serverless in 60 min]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>With serverless backends, front-end developers can build confidently in the cloud from prototype to production without managing infrastructure.</p>
<p>In this session you will learn about tooling, frameworks, and architectural patterns focused on building a web application from front to back. Along the way we will discuss best practices to help you get a started on developing without needing to manage servers. I will demo the solutions, and show how you can integrate these common web app features with minimal code.</p>
<p>If you are a front-end developer wondering how serverless can help you, this session is for you!</p>
<h3 id="lightning-talk">Lightning talk</h3>
<p>Jake Howard will be doing a brief talk on &quot;Wireguard - The Modern VPN Technology&quot;</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/serverless</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/serverless</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/aws.png</url><title>AWS SAM</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Ben Smith, Senior Developer Advocate @ AWS ]]</author></item></channel></rss>