<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Async]]></title><description><![CDATA[An inclusive web tech meetup based in Brighton, UK]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:53:57 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asyncjs.com/feed/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[TypeScript Tales and Tailwind Types]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>NEW VENUE:</strong> We&#39;re trialling a move to <a href="https://runwayea.st/locations/brighton?utm_source=external&amp;utm_medium=event&amp;utm_campaign=sponsorship">Runway East</a>, a brand new space we think makes an even better long-term home for Async meetups. Located <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/oKjqEjpyzC1sLKLp7">a short walk</a> from Brighton railway station on the ground floor of the new York &amp; Elder development.</p>
<p>This month we bring you a special organisers&#39; two-fer presented by Jake and Yann!</p>
<h3 id="the-power-of-typescript">The Power of TypeScript</h3>
<p>Jake will speak on advanced patterns in TypeScript you&#39;ll be glad to know. Along with powerful uses you may wish you didn&#39;t see. <code>&lt;T&gt;</code>rigger warning.</p>
<h3 id="picking-up-tailwind">Picking up Tailwind</h3>
<p>Yann will share a lightning talk on upcoming features in Tailwind that simplify the developer experience and progressively enhance new CSS concepts. Try to <code>@container</code> your excitement.</p>
<p>This session will explore advanced concepts and assumes a working knowledge of either or both tools. All experience levels are welcome as always, but this will be a chance to nerd out if your <code>:nth-of-type()</code> is type safe recursion for breakfast.</p>
<hr>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://runwayea.st/locations/brighton?utm_source=external&amp;utm_medium=event&amp;utm_campaign=sponsorship">Runway East</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RDVL4MIOiG8">online</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/295080379/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/typescript-tales-and-tailwind-types</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/typescript-tales-and-tailwind-types</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/typescript-tailwind.jpg</url><title>Tailwind and TypeScript logos</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Jake &apos;Sid&apos; Smith, Yann Eves ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Good intentions gone bad]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We hope for our web applications to be as beautiful, performant, and accessible as possible; but sometimes... Things get in the way and the outcome is not as good as we hoped. In this talk, I will walk you through a few of my failed attempts at developing accessible web applications. We&#39;ll go through different accessibility assumptions and myths that I wrongly believed to be true and how to avoid them by properly testing for accessibility.</p>
<hr>
<p>Eva Ferreira is a Front-end engineer and professor. She currently works as a UI Lead Developer and has been teaching web technologies at the National Technological University of Argentina for more than ten years.</p>
<p>Throughout her career Eva has been deeply involved in the Argentinian web community. She enjoys giving workshops and talks and since 2015 she has been organizing CSSConf Argentina, an international non-profit event that brings experts from all around the globe to speak about web technologies.</p>
<p>In her spare time she loves reading about CSS, creating animations and playing with her cats.</p>
<hr>
<p>Eva will be joining us from the other side of the world in Argentina via stream link!</p>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gEJiDMw8Lww">online</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/293071307/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/good-intentions-gone-bad</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/good-intentions-gone-bad</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/good-intentions-gone-bad.ojv4.jpg</url><title>Cute red button spells disaster</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Eva Ferreira ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[AI Showcase]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The Async community has been busy prompting so it&#39;s time we give that creativity a stage. An AI Show n&#39; Tell.. a Prompt n&#39; Tell!</p>
<p>We&#39;ll have a line up of lightning talks and demos along with some rigs set up to get hands-on with some different AI tech.</p>
<p>Open to all levels of experience and not limited to the web. While we can get excited by the flashy new possibilities of large language and diffusion models, the debate is rapidly evolving around how to regulate and venture safely towards Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) and perhaps Superintelligence.</p>
<p>Drop a comment on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/293744253/">Meetup</a>, message in the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> or email <a href="mailto:hello@asyncjs.com">hello@asyncjs.com</a> if you&#39;d like to share your own lightning talk or demo.</p>
<hr>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4PRsqP1liCw">online</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/293744253/">meetup.com</a>. We also recommend you join the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ai-showcase</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ai-showcase</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/ai-showcase-2023-sdv2.1.png</url><title>AI Showcase</title><link/></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nodeventure: May the Fourth (Ep. 2 of 2)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>... be with you.</em></p>
<p>This is the second instalment of our <a href="/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep1/">Nodeventure reboot</a>. There are two sessions: <a href="/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep1/">4th May</a> and <a href="/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep2/">11th May</a>. Feel free to come to both or either.</p>
<p>Nodeventure is a multiplayer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_fiction">Text Adventure</a> collaborated in real-time. We&#39;ll continue our Star Wars themed storyline and bring an adventure to life.</p>
<p>WRITERS: Write inspiring descriptions of rooms and objects...<br>ARTISTS: Bring beauty to the world through design...<br>PROGRAMMERS: Extend our super simple game engine...<br>EVERYONE: Help us shape a New Order!</p>
<hr>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/293070432/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep2</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/nodeventure-text.jpg</url><title>Nodeventure</title><link/></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tom Parslow ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nodeventure: May the Fourth (Ep. 1 of 2)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>... be with you.</em></p>
<p>Two timescales have aligned. It&#39;s been a whole decade since our memorable <a href="/nodeventure/">Nodeventure</a> and our next session lands on Star Wars day. Time for a reboot of this Async franchise!</p>
<p>Nodeventure is a multiplayer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactive_fiction">Text Adventure</a> collaborated in real-time. We&#39;ll start with text and a Star Wars themed storyline and bring an adventure to life.</p>
<p>This a chance to work with others on a creative group project, no programming experience necessary. There are two sessions: <a href="/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep1/">4th May</a> and <a href="/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep2/">11th May</a>. Feel free to come to both or either.</p>
<p>WRITERS: Write inspiring descriptions of rooms and objects...<br>ARTISTS: Bring beauty to the world through design...<br>PROGRAMMERS: Extend our super simple game engine...<br>EVERYONE: Help us shape a New Order!</p>
<hr>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/293070419/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/nodeventure-may-the-fourth-ep1</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/nodeventure-text.jpg</url><title>Nodeventure</title><link/></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tom Parslow ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Brains, Spring 2023]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;re back with our popular <strong>&quot;Ask the Brains&quot;</strong> event. The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their <em>&quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot;</em> type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night.</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly Brighton <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">ALT.NET meetup</a>, we will be asking/talking/rambling about everything web-related - 5-10 minutes per topic, such as (thanks ChatGPT):</p>
<ul>
<li>Tabs or spaces for indentation?</li>
<li>Is it okay to use &quot;!important&quot; in CSS?</li>
<li>Is it better to have a light or dark theme for your IDE?</li>
<li>Should you write comments in your code, or is it better to write self-documenting code?</li>
<li>Should you use &quot;camelCase&quot; or &quot;snake_case&quot; for variable names in your code?</li>
<li>Is it better to use single or double quotes in JavaScript?</li>
<li>Is it &quot;gif&quot; or &quot;jif&quot;?</li>
<li>Vim or Emacs?</li>
</ul>
<p>You will be able to submit topics, and event attendees will be able to vote for the topics they would like to discuss. We will run the discussion for about an hour, and afterwards, anyone who wishes can join us nearby for a chat/drink.</p>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>Put your thinking caps on and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask!</p>
<hr>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/291967758/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-2023</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-brains-spring-2023</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/ask-the-brains-2023-sdv1.5.png</url><title>Ask the Brains, Spring 2023</title><link>https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/291967758/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Managing complex UK Energy Interactions with EDA]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The UK energy industry is made up of lots of parties that need to communicate information with each other. Historically the methods used have been largely file based, with EDF needing to share the data internally between many different systems for many different needs.</p>
<p>De-regulation, a more competitive energy market, a rising cost to serve energy and changes to industry processes has meant EDF needs to find ways to drive it&#39;s cost to serve down and stay competitive.</p>
<p>Event Driven Architecture is increasingly becoming the tool that EDF is choosing to manage the complexity of these energy interactions and solve these problems.</p>
<p>Kevin Baldwyn is a lead engineer at EDF energy and in this talk he will explain how EDF is using EDA to manage the complexity of UK Energy Interactions and describe some of the architecture, patterns, lessons learned, and why you may want to start using EDA in your applications.</p>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oNT4-hfJGmM">online</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/291772546/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/edf-uk-energy-industry-interactions-eda</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/edf-uk-energy-industry-interactions-eda</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50601725777_1a756e08d0_b_d.jpg</url><title>&apos;evening energy&apos; by Joachim Aspenlaub Blattboldt</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/blattboldt/50601725777</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Kev Baldwyn ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Alexa to the rescue of inaccessible websites]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The Web is over 30 years old, yet some websites are still not accessible.</p>
<p>This is the tale of how Alexa, with a little bit of help, came to the rescue of a blind person who could not get access to local news.</p>
<p>In this talk, Alex Nicol speaks about accessibility, web crawling, tech-for-good, Alexa, running Ruby on Lambdas, and working on a side project whilst having a six-month-old baby.</p>
<p>Alex Nicol is a web developer working at <a href="https://bridge-u.com/">BridgeU</a> and <a href="https://www.bouncetechnologies.com/">Bounce Technologies</a>. He&#39;s also founded his <a href="https://alexnicol.dev">own consultancy company</a>, specialised in conversational systems and tech-for-good. He previously spent six years at EDF Energy as an R&amp;D engineer specialising in automated voice systems and chatbots.</p>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a> or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uJwvY0K6TkY">online</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/291255649/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/alexa-rescues-inaccessible-sites</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/alexa-rescues-inaccessible-sites</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://live.staticflickr.com/4045/4682461024_10ce18b9ea_b.jpg</url><title>HAL in vector by abelmon007 is licensed under CC BY 2.0.</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/80265839@N00/4682461024</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Alex Nicol ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Silicon Brighton Big Festive Meetup]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As the year draws to a close, Silicon Brighton is excited to host the Big Festive Meetup! This will be a super informal event to bring everyone together across all the meetups we support and celebrate the festive season. Catch up with friends you’ve met through the year, meet new connections from different parts of the tech community, and make new contacts for the year ahead.</p>
<p>The first round is on Silicon Brighton and festive nibbles will be provided. 😊</p>
<p><strong>Dress code</strong>: Festive jumpers optional (but very much encouraged!)</p>
<hr>
<p>Our friends at <a href="https://siliconbrighton.com/">Silicon Brighton</a> who support a <a href="https://siliconbrighton.com/meetup-groups">range of meetup groups</a> in Brighton and Sussex, including Async, are hosting a festive meetup open to their whole network of meetup attendees.</p>
<p>Thanks to their production team we&#39;ve delivered seamless hybrid events and publish recorded talks to our new international community fostered over the last couple of years. Come along and celebrate!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/silicon-brighton-big-festive-meetup</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/silicon-brighton-big-festive-meetup</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/silicon-brighton-big-festive-meetup-2022.png</url><title>Silicon Brighton Big Festive Meetup</title><link>https://hub.siliconbrighton.com/events/98603</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Silicon Brighton ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Async Christmas Quiz 2022]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Hold onto your (Santa) hats for a fresh instalment of the Async Christmas Quiz. Join us as we wind down for 2022’s final first-Thursday-of-the-month in festive December, and we reflect on another fabulous and varied year of Async meetups. This year join us in-person or follow along online.</p>
<p>As with previous years, this won’t be a test of how much JavaScript you know. It’s more like a traditional pub quiz that promises to be humbling at any stage of your career. Come one, come all for this earnest contest for the ultimate prize of trivial knowledge!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz-2022</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz-2022</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/christmas-quiz-2022-sdv1.5.png</url><title>Async Christmas Quiz 2022</title><link>https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/289656145/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Quizmaster Alise ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[2022 International Show 'n' Tell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The November migration of the world&#39;s top web developers to the sunny city of Brighton &amp; Hove can only mean one thing - <a href="https://2022.ffconf.org/">ffconf 2022</a> is coming. So, it&#39;s time for another International Async Show &#39;n&#39; tell! This year&#39;s installment will be <em>on Thursday 10th November</em>.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re interested in giving a talk, we&#39;d love to hear from you. It&#39;s the perfect opportunity to give a peek at your passion project, try out a lightning talk, or just share what&#39;s on your mind. You’ll have five minutes on the night to tell us about something… a project, a library, a technique, a story, or anything else about JavaScript, related tech (HTML, CSS, SVG, etc), or the wider world of web.</p>
<p>If you would like to grab a speaking slot, please leave a comment on the <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/289172125/">meetup event</a> including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your name</li>
<li>Your main website, if you have one</li>
<li>Twitter username, if you have one</li>
<li>A sentence or two about your talk</li>
<li>Any relevant links</li>
</ul>
<p>For a spot of inspiration, take a look at our International Show n&#39; Tells in <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/281637443/">2021</a>, <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/271442327/">2020</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2019/">2019</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2018/">2018</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2017/">2017</a>, <a href="https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2016/">2016</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2015/">2015</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2014/">2014</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2013/">2013</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell-2012/">2012</a>, <a href="http://asyncjs.com/international2011/">2011</a> and <a href="http://asyncjs.com/showntell3/">2010</a>.</p>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person, or online (via Zoom).</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/289172125/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2022</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/international-show-n-tell-2022</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/people/7.jpg</url><title>2022 International Show &apos;n&apos; Tell</title><link>https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/289172125/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[JavaScript Golf 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Come and join us on Thursday October 6th where Tom Parslow - long time Async attendee and chief code typer at <a href="https://buzzshot.com">Buzzshot.com</a>, will task us to solve a series of challenges using JavaScript. The catch - you have to write as little JavaScript as possible. Solve each challenge in the least number of characters to win the game. Imagine the kind of stuff you’d never want to see make it into a real codebase… that’s what we’re looking for!</p>
<p>We are making an effort to ensure that this episode of JavaScript Golf will be suitable for people of all skill levels, so even if you’re reasonably new to JavaScript you should still be able to tackle the challenges (and we’ll be on hand to help if you need it!). Even if you don’t get the fewest number of characters we hope that the majority of attendees will learn a little something about JavaScript from each other along the way. So, don’t forget to bring your laptop, tablet, phone, or whatever you feel comfortable writing code on (with a text editor installed).</p>
<p>As always we welcome people of all backgrounds and experience levels, so whether you&#39;ve got a few years under your belt, or you&#39;re just starting to look into development we&#39;d love to have you along.</p>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a>, or online (via Zoom).</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/288819953/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/javascript-golf-3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/javascript-golf-3</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7379/12758383654_ab4b43d147_z_d.jpg</url><title>Urbanowicz_Krzysztof_GOLF</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/kurbanowicz/12758383654/in/photolist-krq3XY-7hTRLz-9kGXLo-awf96H-9kGXTb-7hTSDX-7hXNAY-kroiT4-6xcLyT-65CWTR-5ds8DL-9kGYdb-9kDVyT-9a69ML-5bCwNN-efi4ma-56hckS-4kQ3Fv-eBP5xt-6QKY1E-c3HmpL-eBRqu3-4ZxP3p-5bCxDW-krpfTx-4ZC1qL-5bCB6j-3vs2Y1-4ZC1u5-4q64vn-4ZxM8Z-4ZxNwg-341zZd-6xj6oL-4ZxNUP-9L3STz-9L3SXt-dxM9tg-dbJjkc-anWVqa-4ZxNqz-5bym8g-4PXK7g-dbJkFS-5bxftP-5bym7V-krp6SB-5bCsCE-5t5bP2-5byh6a</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Tom Parslow ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 ways the 💩 emoji can break your app]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Ever wanted to break someone’s app with a single well placed 💩?</p>
<p>Join us on an adventure though Unicode, UTF-8, glyphs and grapheme clusters.</p>
<p>On Thursday the 1st of September <a href="https://remi-shergold.com">Remi Shergold</a>, web developer and long time Async attendee, shows us ten ways text processing can go wrong.</p>
<p>As always we welcome people of all backgrounds and experience levels, so whether you&#39;ve got a few years under your belt, or you&#39;re just starting to look into development we&#39;d love to have you along.</p>
<p>You will be able to join us in-person at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a>, or online (via Zoom).</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/288002306/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/10-ways-the-poo-emoji-can-break-your-app</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/10-ways-the-poo-emoji-can-break-your-app</guid><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/poo-emoji.jpeg</url><title>Asked DALL-E mini for &quot;evil poo emoji&quot;</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Remi Shergold ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Speed of Write]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;re back at <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a> this coming Thursday for an event that we don&#39;t believe we&#39;ve had anything quite like before.</p>
<p>As with our previous event you will be able to join us in-person, or online (via Zoom).</p>
<p>On Thursday the 4th of August our very own <a href="https://twitter.com/JakeSidSmith">Jake &#39;Sid&#39; Smith</a> - long time Async attendee and now co-organizer - will be running a session on how to improve your coding proficiency by better utilizing the tools at your disposal.</p>
<p>For the first part of the session Jake will be covering some tools, settings, shortcuts, and editor extensions you might not know about, that can help improve your coding quality, speed, and how you work collaboratively. These will mostly center around VSCode, but many will be applicable to other popular editors. There&#39;ll also be some live demos and if there&#39;s time, briefly cover some other tools that you can use alongside your editor.</p>
<p>After this initial demo we&#39;ll open the floor for others to suggest ways in which we can improve how we code - shortcuts, extensions, other tools, etc, have a chat, and demo some of the suggestions. Hopefully by the end of the session everyone will have at least a few little things to take from this to make their development experience easier.</p>
<p>As always we welcome people of all backgrounds and experience levels, so whether you&#39;ve got a few years under your belt, or you&#39;re just starting to look into development we&#39;d love to have you along.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/287513925/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/the-speed-of-write</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/the-speed-of-write</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/the-speed-of-write.gif</url><title>Jim Carey furiously typing on a computer</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Jake &apos;Sid&apos; Smith ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Level-up as a Developer]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Our next event will be the first held at what we hope to be our standard venue for the foreseeable future: <a href="https://www.spacesworks.com/brighton/trafalgar-place/">Spaces</a> - just round the corner from our previous long standing venue.</p>
<p>As with our previous event you will be able to join us in-person, or online (via Zoom).</p>
<p>On Thursday the 7th of July we will be joined by Simon Downes of The Student Room Group who will be giving us a talk on how to level-up as a developer. One of a small few who can take any hat within a development department, be it from a technical level, all the way up to strategic leadership, Simon will explain how to progress a career within development, how you reach the next level, what skills developers need, both technical and soft, and how you can obtain or develop those skills.</p>
<p>As always we welcome people of all backgrounds and experience levels, so whether you&#39;ve got a few years under your belt, or you&#39;re just starting to look into development we&#39;d love to have you along.</p>
<p>If you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/async-web-tech-meetup/events/286855303/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/how-to-level-up-as-a-developer</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/how-to-level-up-as-a-developer</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/level-up.jpg</url><title>Level-up</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Simon Downes ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ask the Hybrid Brains, Spring 2022]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We&#39;re back! After 2 years without human contact you will finally have the opportunity to come face-to-face with like-minded developers and enthusiasts! Can&#39;t make it in-person? Don&#39;t worry, you&#39;ll also be able to join us online.</p>
<p>We are very happy to announce that on the evening of Wednesday 8th June, we will be hosting an in-person hybrid version of our popular <strong>&quot;Ask the Brains&quot;</strong> event for the first time. This means that you will have the ability to join us in-person at <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/pkoNTTRA27bh5GKD8">PLATF9RM</a> in Brighton, or to join us online!</p>
<p>Inspired by the monthly Brighton <a href="http://brightonalt.net/">ALT.NET meetup</a>, we will be asking/talking/rambling about everything web-related - 5-10 minutes per topic.</p>
<p>The aim is to create a friendly environment for everyone to ask their <em>&quot;that thing you&#39;ve never understood but always been too afraid to ask&quot;</em> type questions, plus any other topics you feel like talking about on the night. Topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&#39;m new to development. Where do I get started?</li>
<li>I still don&#39;t get it! What the hell does <code>this</code> mean in Javascript?</li>
<li><code>null</code> or <code>undefined</code>, or is there a case for both</li>
<li>Do we have to accept that JavaScript is now a compiled language</li>
<li>How do you maintain a work-life balance</li>
<li>Should I write unit tests, integration tests, or both?</li>
<li>What are the beneficial aspects of Agile/Scrum, and what do you find less useful.</li>
</ul>
<p>You will be able to submit topics, and event attendees will be able to vote for the topics they would like to discuss. We will run the discussion for about an hour, and afterwards, anyone who wishes can join us nearby for a chat/drink (sorry we can&#39;t take you online folks with us).</p>
<p>The format works best when there is a diverse group of people and opinions in the room, so whether you consider yourself an absolute beginner or a seasoned pro, do come and join.</p>
<p>So, please put your thinking caps on now and start thinking of some questions you would like to ask.</p>
<p>We&#39;re all looking forward to seeing you!</p>
<p>Whether you&#39;re thinking of joining us in-person or online, please sign up to the event on <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Async-Web-Tech-Meetup/events/286286575/">meetup.com</a>. We also highly recommend you sign up to the <a href="https://join.slack.com/t/asyncjs/shared_invite/zt-1aguxx86q-XjF_yWcFoJ8fyYYzoqgDaQ">Async Slack</a> for more info, and updates.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-hybrid-brains</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/ask-the-hybrid-brains</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/hybrid-brains.jpg</url><title>Ask the Hybrid brains</title></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Everyone ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bringing data into your repos using Flat Data]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Flat explores how to make it easy to work with data in git and GitHub. It builds on the <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2020/Oct/9/git-scraping/">“git scraping” approach pioneered by Simon Willison</a> to offer a simple pattern for bringing working datasets into your repositories and versioning them, because developing against local datasets is faster and easier than working with data over the wire.</p>
<p>The team at GitHub Next is focused on enabling new developer workflows. They&#39;ll walk through how their <a href="https://next.github.com/projects/flat-data/">Flat Data project</a> makes it easy to bring data from anywhere on the web directly into your own repos for processing, analyzing, and versioning.</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/flat-data</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/flat-data</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>/img/talks/github-flat-data.png</url><title>Flat Data model</title><link>https://next.github.com/projects/flat-data/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Amelia Wattenberger, Irene Alvarado, Matt Rothenberg ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Svelte Extravaganza]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Since its debut, <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a> has <a href="https://2021.stateofjs.com/en-US/libraries/front-end-frameworks/#front_end_frameworks_experience_ranking">captured an unprecedented level of interest</a> across the web community. Supercharged with <a href="https://kit.svelte.dev/">SvelteKit</a>, we&#39;ll learn about a framework fit for a new generation of production-ready apps.</p>
<p>pngwn joins us from the core Svelte team. Buckle up for a (re-)introduction for beginners and experts alike.</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/svelte-extravaganza</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/svelte-extravaganza</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://kit.svelte.dev/_app/assets/svelte-kit-machine-f9e1f4d5.avif</url><title>Image from SvelteKit website banner</title><link>https://kit.svelte.dev/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ pngwn ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Play them off, Keyboard App: building a virtual keyboard in JavaScript]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know your browser has a whole API dedicated to synthesizing and playing audio?</p>
<p>Sophie will show you how she built a virtual piano using the Web Audio API which plays chords and scales - and the musical theory that shaped it - in this fascinating crossover between music and code.</p>
<hr>
<p>Talk starts at 7.45pm UK time, but the zoom will be open from 7.30pm so feel free to join early for a chinwag.</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/play-them-off-keyboard-app</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/play-them-off-keyboard-app</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1642177201958-782eef7a5c19?auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=680&amp;q=80</url><title>Synthesizer photo by Panagiotis Falcos on Unsplash</title><link>https://unsplash.com/photos/WWvSQBvURdA</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Sophie Koonin ]]</author></item><item><title><![CDATA[Async Christmas Quiz 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back for another Async Christmas Quiz! Despite all the challenges, it’s been a great year in Async-land, with great talks on everything from Accessibility to React Native, as well as some cracking community events such as Ask the Brains and the Show’n’Tell.</p>
<p>Come join us to round it off in style with Quizmaster Daniel van Berzon. As with last year, this will not be a test of how much JavaScript you know as we want to welcome people at all stages of their career; instead it’ll be more of a pub-style quiz but with the focus on having a great time together. So get your metaphorical (or real) Santa hat and beard on and sign up!</p>
]]></description><link>https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://asyncjs.com/christmas-quiz-2021</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 19:30:00 GMT</pubDate><image><url>https://secure.meetupstatic.com/photos/event/9/d/b/0/clean_500080368.jpeg</url><title>Christmas Pug</title><link>https://www.flickr.com/photos/dapuglet/49233631602/</link></image><author>&lt;![CDATA[ Daniel van Berzon ]]</author></item></channel></rss>